Brian Sangermano

Fullstack Developer

PROFILE

I am a system engineer with 5+ years of experience. I have been focused on mastering mobile development while being involved in different projects by using the state of the art JavaScript frameworks such as React Native and Redux.

I am knowledgeable in user interface. I am capable of building dynamic, high performing, and responsive UI for web and mobile applications.

I am equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set. I am also able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

MAIN TECHNOLOGIES

R	≀eact	Ν	lat	ΪV	e
---------------------	-------	---	-----	----	---

React Hooks

Redux

Flow

Typescript

React.js

JavaScript

CSS

Flexbox

HTLM

Node.js

Express

GraphQL

MongoDB

Jest

Git

Jira

SCRUM

EXPERIENCE

Radium Rocket

May 2018 - Current Fullstack Developer

Radium Rocket is a software professional services company that builds engineering teams who develop leading mobile and web products.

Radium Rocket helps businesses of all sizes bring their ideas to life, operating as a true extension of its customer's teams, identifying challenges, designing the product and building innovative software solutions with agile engineering.

Main responsibilities

- Development of mobile applications for Android and iOS with React Native
- Working along with the UI/UX designer to build pixel-perfect UIs across both mobile platforms.
- Building and maintaining React Native applications with clean code, following industry best practices.
- Review pull requests made by projects' teammates.
- Integrating 3rd party libraries into different projects and documentation on newly developed features.
- Creating Unit Tests to ensure developed apps quality.
- Collaborating with team members to establish objectives and deadlines through SCRUM methodologies, using JIRA.
- Provide ongoing feedback to upper management on the current status of the projects.

Technologies: React Native, React-Navigation, Redux, Redux-Saga, React Hooks, React-Hook-Forms, React.js, Flow, Date-fns, Inmutable.js, Axios, CSS, Flexbox, Styled Component, HTML, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Jest, GIT, SCRUM, JIRA.

Dodwing

May 2017 - Apr 2018 Frontend Developer

Software development company with talented people willing to offer engineering and development services to main companies in Europe and the US. Working with agile methodologies, achieve more efficient and faster deliverables that suit the project's needs.

Main responsibilities

- Writed application interface codes using JavaScript following React.js workflows.
- Participated in my first mobile project, implementing mobile-first approach to existing websites using responsive design.
- First approach to features and components with Redux.
- Identified web-based user interactions.
- Troubleshooted interface software and debugged application codes.
- Developed and implemented front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Built reusable code for future use.
- Daily meetings with the client and the rest of the team, showing retrospectives of the work done.

Technologies: JavaScript, React, Redux, Typescript, React Native, CSS, Flexbox, HTML, Node.js, GraphQL, MongoDB, GIT, JIRA, SCRUM.

Universidad Abierta Interamericana

Mar 2016 - May 2017 Frontend Developer

Fundated in 1995, UAI is one of the 3 leading universities of the entire country, offering a vast quantity of career opportunities.

Main responsibilities

- Building responsive features using HTML, CSS, JavaScript based on mockups.
- Building stable and maintainable codebases using React.js.
- Compile and analyze data, processes, and codes to identify problems and areas for improvement.
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues.
- Maintaining and updating the university website.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React.js, GIT, Agile Methodologies.

EDUCATION

Interamerican Open University

2015 - 2020 Systems Engineering

LANGUAGES

• Spanish: Native

• **English**: Intermediate